Register of the Ivan Tikhonovich Gladkii-Gladchenko papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Ivan Tikhonovich Gladkii-Gladchenko papers
1888-1948
2002C76
Hoover Institution Archives
13 manuscript boxes (5.2 linear feet)
Writings and clippings relating to Russian literature and émigré affairs. Includes memoirs and poems.
Gladkii-Gladchenko, Ivan Tikhonovich, 1875-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2002.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Ivan Tikhonovich Gladkii-Gladchenko was a Russian émigré writer who immigrated to Canada and the United States before World War I.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection consists of the literary works of Gladkii-Gladchenko, with some printed matter and a small amount of biographical material. Includes unpublished manuscripts of poetry and memoirs.
Russian literature.; Russians--United States.
- Biographical File, 1888-1948
  Arrangement Statement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - School graduation certificates, 1888 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - "Posemeinyi spisokie Novogrigor'evskago volostnago pravlenia, dlia zapiski krest'ianie i ikhie semeistvie,", 1889 (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - "Avtobiografiia,", 1947-1948 (Box-folder 10: 6-12)
- Writings, 1888-1948
  - "Poems Written in Russia,", 1888-1899 (Box-folder 1: 1-2)
  - "Virgii pisani v Rosii, Kanadi i zluchinikh shtatakh,", 1900-1943 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - "Oposigane z zhittia mikol'skikh baptistiv,", 1903-1909 (Box-folder 1: 4-11)
  - "Ob obshchinnoi zhizni i nastuplenii zolotogo veka na zemle (pis'ma k drugu),", 1904-1945 (Box-folder 1: 12-17, 2: 1-22, 3: 1-12)
  - "Vozzvanie russko-slavianskogo pravdista k russkoi armii, flotu i k germanskim zavoevateliam,", 1905-1917 (Box-folder 3: 13-16)
  - "Rech' I. S. Borisova, chlena Pervoi Gosudarstvennoi Dumy ot Stavropol'skoi gubernii,", 1906 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - "Lichno-semeino-obshchinno-gosudarstvennye pravila,", 1906 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - "Klim Okhvatov" and other poems, 1906-1909 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - "O evreiakh,", 1907 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - "Liubov' Ivana Gladina k Rusi rabochikh i krest'ian,", 1909 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - "V ozhidanii vozhdia Slavarustry,", 1909 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - "O Radishcheve,", 1909 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - "Zhelanie,", 1910-1911 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - "Zhizn' krest'ian Orlova," "Vstrecha dvukh baptistov v Kanade," and "Ivan Zarubaev,", 1911 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - "O prokhode vozhdei trudovogo naroda sredi slavianskikh stran,", 1912 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - "Stikhi napisannye v Kanade,", 1912-1916 (Box-folder 4: 7-9)
  - "Omel'ko Zaporozets',", 1913-1915 (Box-folder 4: 10-28)
  - "O Khriste, Petre i Pavle,", 1915 (Box-folder 4: 29)
  - "Dumy Orlov" and "Vopl' kanadskogo fermera I. Kotlova,", 1916 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - "Prichiny vekovykh bedstvii krest'ian i rabochikh vsekh stran mira,", 1916-1933 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - "Razgovor Soedshtatov s Kanadoi,", 1916 (Box-folder 5: 3-7)
  - "Stikhi napisannye v Soedshtatakh,", 1916-1948 (Box-folder 5: 8-9, 7: 1-15)
  - "Probuzhdenie raba cheloveka ot sna,", 1917 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - "Andrei Mostovoi i ego fermerstvo v Kanade i Sodshtatakh,", 1917-1943 (Box-folder 5: 11-12, 6: 6-10)
  - "Prokliatie interventam v Rossii" and "Ispoved' pered Sovetskoi Rossiiei,", 1919 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - "Pravda o bibleiskom boge Iegove i ego delakh,", 1921 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - "Chomu farmari biduiut v Kanadi i zpoluchenikh shtatakh,", 1922-1930 (Box-folder 5: 15-22)
  - "Pis'mo drugu Kiru Klafloru o V. I. Lenine,", 1924 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - "O Tolstom,", 1928-1929 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - "Ob obshchinnoi zhizni,", 1929 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - "Sila liubvi. Klassy i kommunizm,", 1929 (Box-folder 6: 4-5)
  - "Razgovor dvukh molokan,", 1930-1934 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - "Moral'nye pravila partii kommunistov Sovetskogo Soiuza i drugikh stran,", 1935 (Box-folder 6: 12-13)
  - "Moia epokha,", 1935-1941 (Box-folder 6: 14-18)
  - "O prichine bedstvii fermerov Kanady i Sodshtatov,", 1941 (Box-folder 6: 19-23)
  - "Leninsta-pravdista k vozhdiam rabochikh i krest'ian vsego slavianstva,", 1941-1942 (Box-folder 6: 24-25)
  - "Ivan Dobrov, ego khoziaistvo i semeinaia zhizn',", 1944 (Box-folder 7: 16-19)
  - "Olegoida,", 1944-1946 (Box-folder 7: 20-23, 8: 1-18)
  - "O vechnom mire, kommunizme i ikh osushchestvlenii,", 1945-1946 (Box-folder 8: 19-25, 9: 1-18)
  - "Kem ia byl i est' v oblasti mirovozzreniia,", 1947 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - "Nabroski minuvsnikh razmyshlenii,", 1947 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - "O demokratii Soedshtatov Severnoi Ameriki,", 1947 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - "O politike mirovogo gospodstva lordov Anglii i burzhuev Sodshtatov,", 1947 (Box-folder 11: 1-3)
  - "Pis'mo N. P. Avtonomovu o pravil'nom nazvanii latinskikh bukv v perevode na russkii iazyk,", 1947 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - "Rech' Prezidenta Trumena o pomoshchi Gretsii i Turtsii,", 1947 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - "Tak govoril i uchil Slavarustra pravdist,", 1947-1948 (Box-folder 10: 13-22, 11: 4-16)
  - "Moe mirovozzrenie proshlogo vremeni i nastoiashchego,", 1948 (Box-folder 11: 17)
  - "O reforme angliiskogo iazyka v Soedshtatakh,", 1948 (Box-folder 11: 18-19)
  - "O voinstvennykh tserkovnikakh Soedshtatov i Anglii, ", 1948 (Box-folder 11: 20-22)
  - "Razgovor kommunista Ivana Dolgova s Petrom Grachevym o boge,"", 1948 (Box-folder 11: 23)
  - Notes, 1939-1948 (Box-folder 11: 24)
- Printed Matter and Clippings, 1909-1948
  - Were You Born in June?, 1909 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - Malii molitovnik, 1936 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - A Friend to Man: A Tribute to William Wilson Carson, by George D Lyman, M. D., Stanford University Press, circa 1940 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - Newspaper clippings scrapbooks, 1933-1948 (Box-folder 12: 4-7, 13: 1-6)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes clippings from Russian-language émigré newspapers.